<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Brooklyn CISC</string>

    <string name="math1201title">Calculus I</string>
    <string name="math1201">an introduction to calculus: limits and continuity; derivatives and
        integrals of algebraic, exponential, logarithmic, and trigonometric functions of one
        variable; methods of numerical approximation, and applications of the derivative to
        mathematics, physics, engineering, biology, chemistry, and other fields.</string>
    <string name="math1201texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="math1201credits">4 Credits</string>

    <string name="math1206title">Calculus II</string>
    <string name="math1206">Continuation of Calculus I. Trigonometric and inverse trigonometric
        functions, techniques (closed form and numerical) and applications of integration for
        functions of one variable, improper integrals, l\'Hopital\'s rule, sequences, series, and
        polar coordinates.</string>
    <string name="math1206texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="math1206credits">4 Credits</string>

    <string name="math2501title">Elementary Probability and Statistics</string>
    <string name="math2501">Sample spaces; combinatorial theory; elementary probability; random
        variables; discrete and continuous probability distributions; confidence intervals;
        hypothesis testing. </string>
    <string name="math2501texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="math2501credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="math3501title">Introduction to Probability and Statistics</string>
    <string name="math3501">Sample spaces; combinatorial theory; elementary probability; random
        variables; discrete and continuous probability distributions; moments and moment-generating
        functions; applications. </string>
    <string name="math3501texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="math3501credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="math2001title">Transition to Advanced Mathematics</string>
    <string name="math2001">An introduction to mathematical proofs and a transition to advanced
        mathematics. Elements of mathematical language: basic set theory and logic. Direct proof,
        proof by contrapositive and proof by contradiction. Counterexample and disproof. Relations.
        Functions. Mathematical induction. Countable and uncountable sets. Proofs in elementary
        number theory. Development of the real numbers. Properties of the real number system: order,
        uncountability, completeness, least upper bound property, and the existence of the limits of
        Cauchy sequences.</string>
    <string name="math2001texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="math2001credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="math2101title">Linear Algebra I</string>
    <string name="math2101">Introduction to the concepts of linear algebra. Vector geometry of three
        dimensions.</string>
    <string name="math2101texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="math2101credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="math2206title">Introduction to Differential Equations</string>
    <string name="math2206">Standard methods for solving ordinary differential equations; geometric
        interpretations; problems in physics leading to ordinary and partial differential equations;
        elementary techniques for partial differential equations and separation of variables;
        Fourier series</string>
    <string name="math2206texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="math2206credits">4 Credits</string>

    <string name="math4201title">Advanced Calculus I</string>
    <string name="math4201">Advanced calculus of functions of one variable. Relevant properties of
        the real number system. Properties of continuous functions and uniform continuity.
        Differentiable functions, mean-value theorems. L'Hopital's rule, Taylor's theorem.
        Sequences, series, and improper integrals. </string>
    <string name="math4201texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="math4201credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="math4701title">Numerical Analysis</string>
    <string name="math4701">Introduction to numerical analysis using high-speed computers.
        Fixed-point and floating-point arithmetic; analysis of errors; numerical solution of
        algebraic and transcendental equations and systems of linear equations. Interpolation and
        approximation. Numerical differentiation and integration. Solution of ordinary differential
        equations.</string>
    <string name="math4701texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="math4701credits">4 Credits</string>

    <string name="math2201title">Multivariable Calculus</string>
    <string name="math2201">Continuation of Mathematics 1206. Vectors and parametric equations,
        partial differentiation, multiple integration, line integrals, and Green's theorem.</string>
    <string name="math2201texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="math2201credits">4 Credits</string>
    
    <string name="math3101title">Abstract Algebra I</string>
    <string name="math3101">Elementary theory of groups, rings, and fields; integers, rationals,
        real and complex numbers; elements of number theory, polynomials.</string>
    <string name="math3101texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="math3101credits">3 Credits</string>
    
    <string name="math4101title">Linear Algebra II</string>
    <string name="math4101">Determinants, matrices, and systems of linear equations;
        linear dependence; vector spaces; eigenvalues, and eigenvectors; matrix equations;
        linear transformations; convex sets. </string>
    <string name="math4101texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="math4101credits">4 Credits</string>

    <string name="phil3422title">Philosophical Issues in Cognitive Science</string>
    <string name="phil3422">Introduction to select foundational issues in cognitive science.
        Consideration of such topics as concept formation, meaning, representation, language,
        reasoning, consciousness, rationality, the human mind, and machine intelligence. </string>
    <string name="phil3422texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="phil3422credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc1590title">Management Information Systems</string>
    <string name="cisc1590">Management information systems as a business resource for achieving
        competitive advantage. The major IT applications used in business and how they enable
        competitiveness. The central role that relational databases and data warehouses play in the
        business world. How IT has enabled and accelerated the growth of e-commerce. The role of
        decision support systems and artificial intelligence in business. Overview and impact of IT
        infrastructure design. System Development Lifecycle, project management, outsourcing,
        offshoring and its impact on the US economy. Information security, intellectual property
        rights, copyright and patent law on a national and international level. New trends in
        technology and their potential impact on industry. Case studies and team project are
        required.</string>
    <string name="cisc1590texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc1590credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="psyc1000title">Introductory Psychology</string>
    <string name="psyc1000">An introduction to the major facts, principles, methods, and theories of
        psychology. Topics include the history of psychology, sensory and perceptual processes,
        learning and cognition, motivation and emotion, psychological development, clinical and
        abnormal psychology, and biological, social, and personality determinants of behavior.</string>
    <string name="psyc1000texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="psyc1000credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="psyc3530title">Cognitive Psychology</string>
    <string name="psyc3530">Psychology of memory, problem solving, decision making, language,
        imagery, and other cognitive processes. General overview of the field, including
        information-processing models, studies of thinking, the question of artificial intelligence,
        strategies for improving memory, and other similar areas.</string>
    <string name="psyc3530texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="psyc3530credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="phil3410title">Epistemology: Theory of Knowledge</string>
    <string name="phil3410">Classical and contemporary theories of the nature of knowledge and
        belief. Discussion of skepticism, rationalism, empiricism, coherentism, foundationalism.
        Analysis of such concepts as probability, certainty, perception, evidence, truth.</string>
    <string name="phil3410texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="phil3410credits">4 Credits</string>

    <string name="phil3123title">Twentieth-Century Philosophy</string>
    <string name="phil3123">Such major trends in analytic philosophy as logical atomism, logical
        positivism, and ordinary language analysis. Critical examination of the writings of such
        exponents of these approaches as Russell, Moore, Ayer, Ryle, Austin, and Wittgenstein. Some
        continental philosophers may also be examined."></string>
    <string name="phil3123texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="phil3123credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="phil3401title">Metaphysics</string>
    <string name="phil3401">Classical and contemporary theories of being and reality. Analysis of such
        concepts as particular, quality, relation, personal identity, free will and determinism,
        universals, substance, mind, matter, space, and time. Possibility of metaphysical knowledge.
        The relationship between metaphysics and other disciplines. </string>
    <string name="phil3401texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="phil3401credits">4 Credits</string>

    <string name="phil3420title">Philosophy of Mind</string>
    <string name="phil3420">Philosophic analysis of such mental and psychological concepts as
        intention, want, belief, emotion, will, desire, pleasure, imagination, and thought. Such
        contemporary problems as the identity thesis, behaviorism, the analysis of mental acts, and
        the intentionality thesis. </string>
    <string name="phil3420texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="phil3420credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="phil3601title">Philosophy of Science</string>
    <string name="phil3601">Logical structure of mathematics and of the natural sciences.
        Explanation in the physical sciences. Cognitive status of scientific laws and theories.</string>
    <string name="phil3601texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="phil3601credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc1410title">Philosophy and Artificial Intelligence</string>
    <string name="cisc1410">Contemporary issues in philosophy and psychology, such as the
        mind-machine analogy, the artificial intelligence model of the human mind, intentionality,
        representation, consciousness, concept formation, free will, behaviorism, mechanism.
        Discussion and evaluation of contemporary work in the field.</string>
    <string name="cisc1410texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc1410credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="psyc3580title">Philosophy and Artificial Intelligence</string>
    <string name="psyc3580">Contemporary issues in philosophy and psychology, such as the
        mind-machine analogy, the artificial intelligence model of the human mind, intentionality,
        representation, consciousness, concept formation, free will, behaviorism, mechanism.
        Discussion and evaluation of contemporary work in the field. </string>
    <string name="psyc3580texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="psyc3580credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="phil3423title">Philosophy and Artificial Intelligence</string>
    <string name="phil3423">Contemporary issues in philosophy and psychology such as the mind-
        machine analogy, the artificial intelligence model of the human mind, intentionality,
        representation, consciousness, concept formation, free will, behaviorism, mechanism.
        Discussion and evaluation of contemporary work in the field.</string>
    <string name="phil3423texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="phil3423credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc1050title">Introduction to Computer Applications</string>
    <string name="cisc1050">Introduction to the use of the computer in the home and office. Provides an overview of
    microcomputer applications including a brief introduction to computer concepts, Microsoft
    Windows, Microsoft Office, Microsoft Office Word, Microsoft Office Excel, Microsoft Office
    Access, Microsoft Office PowerPoint, creating Web pages, and integration of the applications.
        (Not open to students who are enrolled in or have completed Computer and Information Science 3800)</string>
    <string name="cisc1050texts">•Microsoft Office 2003: Introductory Concepts and Techniques, Premium Edition
    Shelly Cashman Vermaat (ISBN: 1-418-85931-1)</string>
    <string name="cisc1050credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc5001title"> Independent Study and Research I</string>
    <string name="cisc5001">Independent research study or project supervised by a faculty member;
        approved reading; project report or written examination. </string>
    <string name="cisc5001texts">None</string>
    <string name="cisc5001credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3810title">Database Systems</string>
    <string name="cisc3810">Introduction to database systems. Comparison to file processing systems.
        Data models. Relational, hierarchical, and network systems. Database design. Normal forms.
        Study of several real-world database management systems, with an emphasis on microcomputer
        applications. Database recovery query and transaction processing, concurrency. Distributed
        and object-oriented databases.</string>
    <string name="cisc3810texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc3810credits">3 Credits</string>


    <string name="cisc3610title">Introduction to Multimedia Programming</string>
    <string name="cisc3610">In-depth study of multimedia programming. Multimedia authoring tools.
        Graphical user interface design. Multimedia project development. Effective use of media
        elements in a computer application and on the World Wide Web. </string>
    <string name="cisc3610texts">•Multimedia Concepts, Enhanced Edition—Illustrated Introductory, Shuman,
    Thomson Learning\n
    •Macromedia Director MX 2004 Bible (Bible): Brian Underdahl, John R.
    Nyquist, Robert Martin, Wiley</string>
    <string name="cisc3610credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3820title">Introduction to Modeling and Simulation</string>
    <string name="cisc3820">Introduction to simulation and comparison with other techniques.
    Discrete simulation models. Introduction to queueing theory and stochastic processes. Simulation
    methodology including generation of random numbers and variables, design of simulation
    experiments for optimization, analysis of data generated by simulation experiments.
    Variance reduction in simulation, importance sampling. Quasi-Monte Carlo integration
    methods, sequential Monte Carlo methods. Applications of simulation.</string>
    <string name="cisc3820texts">•Simulation, 3rd Edition, by Sheldon M. Ross, Academic Press, 2002.</string>
    <string name="cisc3820credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3415title">Principles of Robotics</string>
    <string name="cisc3415">Basic principles of mobile robotics: architectures, mathematical
        foundations, control algorithms, human robot interaction, and practical applications.
        Applications include robots in the home, and robots in search and rescue work. Involves
        programming different kinds of robots.</string>
    <string name="cisc3415texts">•Introduction to Autonomous Mobile Robot, Siegwart and
        Nourbakhsh, MIT Press, 2003.</string>
    <string name="cisc3415credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3410title">Artificial Intelligence</string>
    <string name="cisc3410">Techniques for making computers exhibit intelligent behavior.
        Topics covered are taken from the areas of problem solving, perception, game playing,
        knowledge representation, natural language understanding, programs that learn
        (adaptive programs), expert systems, and programming languages for work in artificial
        intelligence. </string>
    <string name="cisc3410texts">•Stuart Russell and Peter Norvig. Artificial Intelligence: A Modern
        Approach (second edition), ISBN 0-13-790395-2, Prentice Hall. </string>
    <string name="cisc3410credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3390title">Compiler Construction</string>
    <string name="cisc3390">Review of programming language structures, translation, loading, execution, and storage
    allocation. Compilation of simple expressions and statements. Organization of a compiler
    including compile-time and run-time symbol tables, lexical scan, object code generation,
    error diagnostics, object code optimization techniques, and overall design. Use of
    compiler-writing languages and bootstrapping</string>
    <string name="cisc3390texts">•Compilers: Principles, Techniques, and Tools. By: A. V. Aho, M. S.
        Lam, R. Sethi, and J. Ullman. </string>
    <string name="cisc3390credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3340title">Computer Networks and Protocols</string>
    <string name="cisc3340">Computer networks and protocols. Network topologies and switching
        mechanisms. Protocol concepts and characteristics. Network protocol architectures.
        Physical layer concepts. Data link layer functions and protocols. Network layer
        concepts. Network access protocols. Local area networks and protocols. Internetworking.
        Transport layer functions and protocols. Upper layer issues and approaches. Application
        program interfaces. Network examples.</string>
    <string name="cisc3340texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc3340credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3240title">Cryptography and Cryptanalysis</string>
    <string name="cisc3240">An introduction to mathematical cryptography. Various cryptographic
        systems. Basic cryptanalytic attacks. Modern cryptographic systems; authentication;
        factorization attacks. This course is the same as Mathematics 3107 </string>
    <string name="cisc3240texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc3240credits">4 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3230title">Theoretical Computer Science</string>
    <string name="cisc3230">Overview of theoretical computer science. Formal language theory,
        computability theory. Finite automata, context-free and regular grammars, push-down automata
        , and Turing machines. Other models of computation, including recursive functions.
        Universal program and unsolvability.</string>
    <string name="cisc3230texts">•Michael Sipser; Introduction to the Theory of Computation. (1997) </string>
    <string name="cisc3230credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3171title">Introduction to Software Engineering</string>
    <string name="cisc3171">A broad view of software engineering that introduces a variety of
        software engineering techniques that can be applied to practical software projects. Topics
        include: process models, software specification, software design, software development
        methods and tools, verification and validation, reliability, and human factors.</string>
    <string name="cisc3171texts">•Fundamentals of Software Engineering, Carlo Ghezzi, Mehdi Jazayeri
        , and Dino Mandrioli, Prentice-Hall, 1991, ISBN: 0-13-820432-2,</string>
    <string name="cisc3171credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3160title">Programming Languages</string>
    <string name="cisc3160">The design, implementation, and evolution of programming languages.
        Language features and their effects upon translation and run-time environments. Languages
        studied are chosen for their historical and current significance, programming paradigm, and
        run-time environment. Syntax and semantic specification; formal grammars. </string>
    <string name="cisc3160texts">•Programming Languages Concepts and Construct, Second Edition, by:
        Ravi Sethi Addison-Wesley Publishing, 1996</string>
    <string name="cisc3160credits">4 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc1180title">Introduction to C++ for Programmers</string>
    <string name="cisc1180">Intensive introduction to programming in C++ for students who have
        completed a programming course in another language.</string>
    <string name="cisc1180texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc1180credits">2 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3325title">Information Security</string>
    <string name="cisc3325">Principles and practices of computer and network security. Fundamental
        concepts and principles of computer security, basic cryptography, authentication and access
        control, Internet vulnerability (malware, DoS attacks, etc), intrusion detection systems,
        firewalls, software and operating system security, database security, web and wireless
        security, managerial and ethical issues in computer security. Lab and project activities
        such as the use of network probing for illustrative and diagnostic purposes; security tool
        choice, deployment and configuration; secure programming techniques. </string>
    <string name="cisc3325texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc3325credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3315title">Digital Computer Systems</string>
    <string name="cisc3315">Functional components of computer systems: registers, counters, coders,
        multiplexers. Data representation. Memory, register, and bus transfer operations. Basic
        computer organization and design. Central processor organization. Hardwired and
        microprogrammed control units. Bus structures. Arithmetic logic units. Memory and I/O
        organization. Laboratory experiments on computer operations. Design of a digital computer system.</string>
    <string name="cisc3315texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc3315credits">4.5 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3345title">Computer Networks</string>
    <string name="cisc3345">A course on computer networks and protocols. Network topologies and switching
    mechanisms. Protocol concepts and characteristics. Network protocol architectures. Data
    link layer functions and protocols. Network layer concepts. Network access protocols.
    Local area networks and protocols. Internetworking. Transport layer functions and
    protocols. Application layer protocols. The World Wide Web. Network security.</string>
    <string name="cisc3345texts">•Data and Computer Communications, 8th ed. by - W. Stallings
    (Pearson /Prentice-Hall)\n•(Reference Textbook) Computer Networking with Internet Protocols
        and Technology by - W. Stallings (Pearson /Prentice-Hall) </string>
    <string name="cisc3345credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3343title">Telecommunications</string>
    <string name="cisc3343">Introduction to telecommunications. Data transmission fundamentals. Data
        encoding. Modems. Digital subscriber lines. Data compression. Physical layer interfaces.
        Transmission error control. Telephony signaling. Wireless and cellular communications.
        Asynchronous Transfer Mode (ATM) Networks. Integrated Services Digital Networks (ISDN</string>
    <string name="cisc3343texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc3343credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc2531title">Operations Management</string>
    <string name="cisc2531">Study in managerial decision making to solve a wide range of operating management problems.
    Topics covered include: planning, evaluation and control of operations; forecasting and inventory
    management; scheduling; project design and management; resource allocation; queuing models;
    quality of the work environment; and technological change. Design and implementation of
    management strategy will be emphasized through computer simulation, problems, and cases. This
    course is the same as BUSN 3430</string>
    <string name="cisc2531texts">•Quantitative Analysis for Management /10e, by Render, Stair and Hanna. Pearson Prentice Hall
    (with CD) ISBN 0-13-603625-8.</string>
    <string name="cisc2531credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc1530title">Electronic Commerce</string>
    <string name="cisc1530">How the Internet can be used to conduct business. Topics covered
        include: Internet hardware and software, tools and technologies for creating a Web site,
        characteristics of successful Web sites, new technologies, the future of the Internet, Web
        communication strategies, security issues, legal and ethical issues, Internet information
        services, data mining, global E-commerce. Case studies of successful E-commerce businesses
        will be examined.</string>
    <string name="cisc1530texts">•E- commerce: business, technology, society. by Kenneth C. Laudon
        and Carol Guercio Traver. (3nd ed., Addison-Wesley, 2003)</string>
    <string name="cisc1530credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc2532title">Information Systems Project Management</string>
    <string name="cisc2532">
        Information system project definition, management and implementation using automated project
        management software. Analytical and automated methods for management of project time,
        resources, cost and risk. Ensuring system quality and usability.</string>
    <string name="cisc2532texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc2532credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc1580wtitle">Seminar in Computer-Assisted Management Games</string>
    <string name="cisc1580w">Simulation of a business environment providing practice in various
        management functions such as objective setting, planning, supervising, organizing,
        controlling, problem solving, and leadership. Emphasis on presentation and communication
        skills and presenting results and their justification. Includes games involving competition
        in the marketplace and use of knowledge-based management software for the business executive
        . The desired course objectives are enhanced negotiating skills, improved personnel
        observations, and optimized managerial behaviors. Writing-intensive course.</string>
    <string name="cisc1580wtexts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc1580wcredits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="econ2200title">Elementary Microeconomics</string>
    <string name="econ2200">Basic laws and principles of economic science. Value, price, and
        distribution. Preparation for more comprehensive studies involving application of the tools
        of analysis to economic problems.</string>
    <string name="econ2200texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="econ2200credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="busn2100title">Elementary Macroeconomics</string>
    <string name="busn2100">Contemporary economic analysis of the operation of the United States
        economy. Role of markets and the determination of the overall level of economic activity.
        Dynamic process of growth, inflation, and international trade.</string>
    <string name="busn2100texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="busn2100credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="busn3200title">Principles of Management</string>
    <string name="busn3200">Principles of management. Functions of the manager. Organization and
        operation of American business. Management processes, concepts, and specific problems of
        production, management, labor relations, marketing, financing, decision making and
        accounting. Lectures, discussions, and case studies. </string>
    <string name="busn3200texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="busn3200credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="busn3310title">Corporation Financial Management</string>
    <string name="busn3310">Basic problems faced by financial managers. Goals and functions of
        financial managers, tools of financial analysis, forecasting funds requirements, management
        of current assets, short-, intermediate-, and long-term financing.</string>
    <string name="busn3310texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="busn3310credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="busn3410title">Fundamental Methods of Mathematical Economics I</string>
    <string name="busn3410">Mathematical tools necessary for advanced study. Application of
        differential calculus and matrix algebra to economic analysis. Consideration of static,
        comparative static, and optimization models</string>
    <string name="busn3410texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="busn3410credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="econ3400title">Introduction to Economic and Business Statistics</string>
    <string name="econ3400">Descriptive statistics including measures of central tendency,
        dispersion, and skewness. Probability and theoretical probability distributions including
        the binomial function and the normal curve. Sampling, estimation, and test of hypothesis.
        Simple correlation and regression analysis. Applications from social sciences. This course
        is the same as Business 3400</string>
    <string name="econ3400texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="econ3400credits">4 Credits</string>

    <string name="acct2001title">Introductory Accounting</string>
    <string name="acct2001">Introduction to the concepts and principles of accounting. Techniques of
        data accumulation. Nature and interpretation of financial statements. Corporate
        accounting.</string>
    <string name="acct2001texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="acct2001credits">4 Credits</string>

    <string name="psyc3400title">Statistical Methods in Psychological Research</string>
    <string name="psyc3400">Basic descriptive and inferential statistics including the elements of
        experimental designs in psychological research. STEM variant course</string>
    <string name="psyc3400texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="psyc3400credits">4 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3800title">Advanced Personal Computer Techniques for Business
    Applications </string>
    <string name="cisc3800">In-depth analysis of software and hardware available for current business applications.
    Advanced use of application packages. Critique and comparison of current application
    software. Designing a proper interface. Examination of current trends toward office
    automation. System design and analysis. </string>
    <string name="cisc3800texts">•biweekly readings from PC magazine</string>
    <string name="cisc3800credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc1150title">UNIX Shell Programming</string>
    <string name="cisc1150">The shell programming language. Command structure and I/O redirection. Control structures,
        metacharacters, process environment. Shell scripts, exception handling, numerical and string facilities,
        recursion. Filter programs, the software tools approach, pipeline programming. Regular expression pattern
        matching. Quoting. Subshells. Remote shell programs. Background processes, shell demons, process management.</string>
    <string name="cisc1150texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc1150credits">2 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3330title">Foundations of Parallel and Distributed Computing</string>
    <string name="cisc3330">Survey of parallel and distributed hardware fundamentals, including SMP machines,
    clusters, grids, and networks of workstations. Introduction to the design of parallel
    algorithms and the analysis of their efficiency. Survey of software issues for parallel and
    distributed computation including message passing and shared memory, processes and
    threads, client/server and peer to peer, and issues of synchronization. Complexity
    considerations and the limits of parallelism.</string>
    <string name="cisc3330texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc3330credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3350title">Workstation Programming</string>
    <string name="cisc3350">Programming techniques for development of applications on networks of workstations.
    Process environments, file system issues. Concurrent programming, interprocess
    communication. Graphical user interfaces, event-driven programming. Distributed
    programming; remote process creation, the client-server model, message passing.</string>
    <string name="cisc3350texts">•Kay A. Robbins and Steven Robbins, Unix System Programming, 2nd edition, Prentice
    Hall, 2003. (RR) </string>
    <string name="cisc3350credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc4331title">System and Network Administration</string>
    <string name="cisc4331">Installation, configuration, and maintenance of an operating system.
        Configuration of routers, networks, and sub-networks. Installation, configuration, and
        maintenance of network utilities such as email, web server, and other services. Use of
        network diagnostic tools. Identification and repair of network and configuration problems. </string>
    <string name="cisc4331texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc4331credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc4335title">Parallel and Distributed Computing</string>
    <string name="cisc4335">Development of parallel and distributed applications. Examples taken from scientific
    programming, artificial intelligence, operations research, and management science.
    Symmetric models and asymmetric models. Client-server. Threaded programming. Data
    parallelism versus algorithmic parallelism. Issues of resource utilization, program
    decomposition, performance, probability, debugging. Use of formal methods, faulttolerance,
    security and other distributed systems issues.</string>
    <string name="cisc4335texts">•Introduction to CUDA Programming, Volume I, CUDA Technical Training,Nvidia
    Corp., 2008\n
    •Parallel Processing with CUDA, Tom R. Halfhill, Microprocessor Report, January 28,
    2008. </string>
    <string name="cisc4335credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc1600title">Introduction to Multimedia Computing</string>
    <string name="cisc1600">Introduction to multimedia topics, including: web design, game design, animation, data
    visualization, simulation and robotics. Introduction to multimedia hardware and software, including
    game boxes. Human interface design and input using multimedia devices. Graphical and other forms
    of output to multimedia devices. Emphasis on design and creation of web pages with HTML and
    cascading style sheets; interactive, graphical web-based programs; simple computer games, movies
    and narratives. Computer-based sound editing. Introduction to agent-based programming for
    simulations and robotics. Uses of multimedia in industry. Hands-on exercises.</string>
    <string name="cisc1600texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc1600credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3650title">Human-Computer Interaction</string>
    <string name="cisc3650">Overview of computer-human interfaces with an emphasis on innovative approaches.
    Principles of computer-human interaction. Ubiquitous computing and tangible interfaces.
    Interfaces employing speech recognition and computer vision. Sensor technologies.
    Computer supported cooperative work. Virtual and augmented realities. </string>
    <string name="cisc3650texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc3650credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3660title">Game Programming</string>
    <string name="cisc3660">Game programming techniques. 2D and 3D games. Data representations of virtual elements.
    Visualizing the 3D game environment. Controlling motion and behaviors. Interaction control.
    Game architectures, including multi-player games and message passing. Managing complexity.
    Teamwork to create a 3D game using a 3D multi-player game engine. Interaction with game
    development professionals regarding state-of-the-art hardware and software technology for game
    creation and adaptation. </string>
    <string name="cisc3660texts">•A. Watt and F. Policarpo, 3D Games: Volume I: Real-Time Rendering and Software
    Technology, Addison Wesley, 2000. </string>
    <string name="cisc3660credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3665title">Game Design</string>
    <string name="cisc3665">Introduction to designing the intelligence behind computer games. Fundamentals
        of designing, programming and troubleshooting game behavior. Documenting and critiquing design.
        Multi-week small-group projects in game design. </string>
    <string name="cisc3665texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc3665credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3620title">Computer Graphics</string>
    <string name="cisc3620">Fundamentals of computer graphics programming. Graphics hardware and software standards. 2D
    geometric primitives and raster images. 3D object representations. Data structures, algorithms, and the
    graphics pipeline. Graphical user interfaces. Underlying concepts in computer graphics systems,
    including games, animation, modeling, rendering, and paint systems.</string>
    <string name="cisc3620texts">•Angel, Interactive Computer Graphics: A Top-Down Approach Using OpenGL,5/E, AddisonWesley.</string>
    <string name="cisc3620credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3630title">Multimedia Computing</string>
    <string name="cisc3630">Surveys the interrelationship of state-of-the-art communication, and computer technology. Hardware,
    software and system design issues in the multimedia presentation of information. Multimedia
    standards. Audio and video compression techniques. Hypermedia database systems. Programming and
    the use of multimedia authoring systems. Survey of representative hypermedia applications.</string>
    <string name="cisc3630texts">•Multimedia: Making it Work, 7th edition, Tay Vaughn, McGraw Hill, 2006\n
    •Johnson, Steven M, Macromedia Director 8 Shockwave Studio (Complete), Course
    Technology, 2001. </string>
    <string name="cisc3630credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc1110title">Introduction to Programming Using C++</string>
    <string name="cisc1110">Algorithms, computers and programs. Writing, debugging, and testing programs. Loops and
    conditional control structures. Functions and parameter passing. Arrays, strings and simple
    classes. Sorting, searching and other basic algorithms. Input and output. Programming
    applications selected from various disciplines. History and basic concepts of computer science.</string>
    <string name="cisc1110texts">•Problem Solving With C++ (authors: J. Jones and K. Harrow)\n•Workbook for C++ (author: Langsam)</string>
    <string name="cisc1110credits">4 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3110title">Advanced Programming Techniques</string>
    <string name="cisc3110">A second course in programming. Advanced programming techniques emphasizing
    reliability, maintainability, and reusability. Module design and multi-file programs.
    Abstract data types. Objects, classes, and object-oriented design. Storage class and scope.
    Addresses, pointers, and dynamic storage allocation. Test suites, test drivers, and testing
    strategies; debugging, assertions, and an introduction to formal techniques. Recursion and
    function parameters. (Not open to students who are enrolled in or have completed
    CISC 3130.) </string>
    <string name="cisc3110texts">•Gaddis, T., Walters, J. and Muganda, G. Starting Out with Gaddis: Early Objects, 6th
    edition, Addison Wesley, 2007.\n•Peek, J, Todino-Gonquet, G. and Strang , J., Learning the Unix Operating System, 5th
    edition, O.Reilly, 2001</string>
    <string name="cisc3110credits">4 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3120title">Design and Implementation of Software Applications I</string>
    <string name="cisc3120">Introduction to essential topics for modern software application development: Graphical User
    Interface (GUI) programming and human-computer interaction; computer graphics; networks,
    security, and client-server computing, including web applications. Code development by example,
        and modification of instructor-authored code using Java, emphasizing its graphics and
    networking capabilities. Contemporary programming development environments and tools
    including Application Programming Interfaces (APIs) and Integrated Development Environments
    (IDEs). Students should be prepared to take CISC 3140 in the following semester.</string>
    <string name="cisc3120texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc3120credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3130title">Data Structures</string>
    <string name="cisc3130">Stacks and their implementations. Prefix, postfix, and infix notation. Queues and linked
    lists and their implementations. Binary and general trees and their implementations and
    traversals. Sorting and searching techniques. Graph algorithms. </string>
    <string name="cisc3130texts">•Data Structures Using C and C++ second edition, by: Langsam, Tenenbaum,
    and Augenstein</string>
    <string name="cisc3130credits">4 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3140title">Design and Implementation of Software Applications II</string>
    <string name="cisc3140">Continuation of CISC 3120. Emphasis on building and testing a system designed and prototyped
    in CISC 3120. Emphasis on software development, database systems, intelligent systems and
    software engineering. This course should be taken the semester after CISC 3120</string>
    <string name="cisc3140texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc3140credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3150title">Object-Oriented Programming</string>
    <string name="cisc3150">Principles and implementation issues in object-oriented programming languages, including:
    memory and run-time models; encapsulation, inheritance and polymorphism; generics.
    Collections and other frameworks and hierarchies. Effects of binding time considerations on
    language design and implementation. Introduction to design patterns, such as adapter,
    singleton, and model-view-controller. Formal design specifications such as UML. Case studies
    chosen from multiple languages such as C++, Java and Smalltalk.</string>
    <string name="cisc3150texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc3150credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc2210title">Introduction to Discrete Structures</string>
    <string name="cisc2210">Elementary set theory, functions, relations, and Boolean algebra. Switching circuits, gating
    networks. Definition and analysis of algorithms. Applications of graph theory to computer science.
    Related algorithms. Introduction to combinatorial computing and counting arguments. Introduction
    to error analysis. </string>
    <string name="cisc2210texts">•Kenneth H. Rosen, Discrete Mathematics and its Applications, McGraw Hill, 5th Ed., ISBN 0-07-
    289905\n•Students Solutions Guide, McGraw Hill, ISBN 0-07-2336102 </string>
    <string name="cisc2210credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc2820wtitle">Computers and Ethics</string>
    <string name="cisc2820w">Analysis of ethical issues pertaining to computers and the workplace, anonymity and
    privacy, copyright and patent law (as applied to software), computer crime, security,
    unauthorized use, codes of conduct for computer professionals, access and availability of
    computing technologies. Application of theoretical frameworks such as virtue ethics,
    deontological theories and utilitarianism to the ethical problems encountered in
    computing technologies. Writing intensive course. (This course is the same as Philosophy
    3318)</string>
    <string name="cisc2820wtexts">•Richard A. Spinello, Cyberethics: Morality and Law in Cyberspace, Jones and
    Bartlett Publishers, Massachusetts, 2005. ISBN: 0-7637-0064-9\n
    •Richard A. Spinello and Herman T. Tavani, Readings in Cyberethics (2nd ed.),
    Jones and Bartlett Publishers, Massachusetts, 2005. ISBN: 0-7637-2410-6 </string>
    <string name="cisc2820wcredits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3310title">Principles of Computer Architecture</string>
    <string name="cisc3310">Introduction to digital logic. Basic digital circuits. Boolean algebra and combinational logic, data
    representation and transfer, digital arithmetic. Instruction sets. Introduction to assembly languages:
    ALU and memory reference instructions, flow control, subroutine linkage, arrays and structures.
    Memory. I/O systems. Performance. Relationship between software and architecture. (Not open to
    students who are enrolled in or have completed Computer and Information Science 3305 [27] or
    3315 [28].)</string>
    <string name="cisc3310texts">Up to instructor</string>
    <string name="cisc3310credits">4 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3320title"> Operating Systems </string>
    <string name="cisc3320">Design and implementation of operating systems for large computers.
    Multiprogramming, multiprocessing, time sharing. Resource allocation and scheduling.
    Communications, conversational computing, computer networks. Memory protection,
    interrupts, segmentation, paging, and virtual memories. </string>
    <string name="cisc3320texts">•Operating System Concepts (6th or 7th edition), by: Silberschatz, Galvin and Gagne </string>
    <string name="cisc3320credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc3220title">Analysis of Algorithms</string>
    <string name="cisc3220">Algorithms, data structures, and their analysis. Applications for and solution to recurrence problems.
    Upper and lower bounds on complexities of various problems. Classification by design structures.
    Sorting methods, graph and selection algorithms. Pattern matching. Efficient computation of
    transitive closure and equivalences. NP-completeness. </string>
    <string name="cisc3220texts">•Baase, Sara and Van Gelder. Computer Algorithms: Introduction to Design and Analysis, 3rd
    ed., Addison-Wesley. </string>
    <string name="cisc3220credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc4610title">Multimedia Databases</string>
    <string name="cisc4610">Multimedia data types and formats. Multimedia computer database design
        issues. Indexing and automated retrieval of text documents, audio files, images and video.
        Techniques and data structures for efficient multimedia similarity search. System support
        for distributed multimedia databases. Measurement of multimedia information retrieval
        effectiveness. Products, applications, and new developments.</string>
    <string name="cisc4610texts">•L. Dunckley, Multimedia Databases: An Object-Relational Approach,
        Addison Wesley, 2003. </string>
    <string name="cisc4610credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="cisc4900title">Independent and Group Projects I</string>
    <string name="cisc4900">Planning and development of a real computer systems project supervised by a faculty member.
    Achievement measured by demonstrable attainment of the project’s goals. CISC 4900 is required of all CIS majors.
    Department permission is required for registration. Completion of a major computer science project (involving
    approximately 15 hours/week of work), plus tutoring. Students may find their own project, within or
    outside the school. Many students use projects at work for their project.  </string>
    <string name="cisc4900texts">None</string>
    <string name="cisc4900credits">3 Credits</string>

    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_courses_info">CoursesInfo</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="section_format">Hello World from section: %1$d</string>
</resources>

